Guide to the Harry Clement Brogan Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harry Clement Brogan papers
1898-1965
1917-1923
MS 1769
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
The papers of Harry Clement Brogan consist of printed materials, memorabilia, and photographs relating to Brogan's student years at Yale, particularly commencement activities in 1920 and 1923, as well as his participation in Yale's Reserve Officers' Training Corps. A personal collection of vintage postcards depicting Connecticut towns is included in the papers.
Brogan, Harry Clement, 1898-1969
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Helen Louise Brogan, 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Harry Clement Brogan was born in Roxbury, Massachusetts, on February 28, 1898. He graduated with a B.A. degree from Yale College in 1920. During his 1917-1918 academic year he was a private in Battery D of the Yale Reserve Officers' Training Corps. He was later commissioned as a second lieutenant before being transferred to Camp Zachary Taylor where he was discharged on December 18, 1918. In 1923 he received his LL.B. degree from the Yale Law School. He practiced law in New London, Connecticut, and was the corporation counsel for the town of Groton. On June 4, 1924, he married Dorcas Gertrude Whaley, and had two children. Brogan died on July 16, 1969, in New London.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Harry Clement Brogan consist of printed materials, memorabilia, and photographs relating to Brogan's student years at Yale, particularly commencement activities in 1920 and 1923, as well as his participation in Yale's Reserve Officers' Training Corps. A personal collection of vintage postcards depicting Connecticut towns is included in the papers.
Brogan, Harry Clement, 1898-1969; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1920; Yale University. Reserve Officers' Training Corps; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Yale University
    - Class of 1920
      - Commencement and class day events [printed materials/memorabilia], 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Clay pipes, [1920] (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Thirty-fifth reunion, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Class of 1923 [commencement program], 1923 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Corbey Court and Phi Delta Phi, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Football [memorabilia], 1920, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous printed materials [includes 1898 junior promenade prom book, student handbook, programs of social events], 1898, 1916-1922, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Reserve Officers' Training Corps (ROTC)
      - Memorabilia [patches, pins, pouch, rulers], [1917-1918] (Box 1, Folder 8 - 9)
      - Photograph, 1918 September (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Printed materials, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Term examinations, 1917, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Yale Law School [semi-annual examinations], 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials [theater programs, etc.], 1918-1924, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Postcards [primarily of Connecticut and New England towns], 1903-1955 (Box 2, Folder 15 - 19)
  - Oversize
    - Photographs
      - Yale buildings/landmarks, 1901, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Class of 1920 graduation (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Class of 1920 [forty-fifth reunion], 1965 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Law School class of 1923 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Diploma of Harry Clement Brogan, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "The Probable Error" [newspaper published at Camp Zachary Taylor], 1918 November 15, December 4 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Charcoal sketch of unidentified woman, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)